my power lifters are going to want to
pay close attention to this one I've
reviewed a handful of weight lifting
belts for you guys already and guess
what I've got another one for you today
I've been using the gym Reaper's seven
millimeter weightlifting belt a lot
lately and I'm excited to break it down
for y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
around I've got the seven millimeter
weightlifting belt from gym Reapers now
in this video I'm going to tell you
everything that you need to know about
this belt from the price the features of
course the pros and cons and you know
more importantly who should or maybe
should not purchase one of these but
before I get going with all that I gotta
let you know we've reviewed a lot of
weightlifting belts on barbin.com so if
you want to browse our best list just
simply search bar Ben best weight
lifting belts our list is going to pull
right up for you and you can find out
for yourself which ones that we like the
best
foreign
[Music]
well I personally love the fully leather
build it's going to provide you with a
high level of support which is you know
definitely beneficial as you're going to
do some heavy squats you know that way
you don't hurt yourself I also really
like this dual prong steel Buckle right
here it's going to keep the belt nice
and tight against your body as well as
just keeping it secure you know it's not
going to come loose as you're working
out the taper right here on the front is
really nice in my opinion as well you
know not every single belt is tapered in
the front and this is really going to
allow you to breathe properly when
you're working out you know it's not
going to pinch your skin underneath your
ribs it's also going to allow you to
stay pretty mobile as well as you're
lifting and it's priced for right around
60 bucks which is a pretty solid deal in
my opinion considering it is in fact a
fully leather belt
foreign
so let's talk about a few issues you
might experience with this belt now if
you're somebody who does a whole lot of
Olympic and Crossfit style lifts this
really might not be the ideal belt for
you that's because it's you know fully
leather and it's my opinion it's
probably going to be best suited for
power lifting so if you are one of those
people I suggest checking out some nylon
belts instead of a fully leather belt
like this one I personally like the
taper front but not everybody's going to
be crazy about that because you know
technically you have less surface area
for your core to brace against and
lastly you know it does provide you with
a high level of support you know I gotta
say but it might not provide the same
exact amount of support as a 10
millimeter or 13 millimeter belt can and
you know if that's something you're
interested in looking at gym Reapers
actually has both of those options
available
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the money with
the gym Reaper's seven millimeter
weightlifting belt now it's listed for
right around 60 bucks on the Jim
Reaper's website as well as Amazon
considering this is once again made of
100 leather I think this is a really
solid deal you know there's a lot of
leather belts out there that are
basically double the price I'm talking
anywhere from 120 bucks 150 maybe even
more now a lot of those options are also
Thicker Than This belt so that could
definitely you know play into effect on
that price but once you really factor in
the fact that this is a fully leather
belt it's probably going to last you 10
years maybe even longer I think it's a
no-brainer purchase if you are in fact
looking for a belt for your power lifts
[Music]
okay so let's break down the build and
some of the features now with this belt
you know once again it does have a
thickness of seven millimeters and this
is going to be really helpful as you're
lifting some heavy weight it's going to
keep you in proper form it's also going
to keep you from getting hurt which you
know is obviously a very crucial thing
now it is made from 100 premium leather
but on the inside you actually have
suede right here it's gonna be pretty
comfortable you know if it's on your
skin it's also going to help you out in
terms of moisture control now this is in
black leather it's the only color
available which you know black never
goes out of style so I don't think it's
something you need to worry about you do
have this dual prong steel Buckle right
here it's going to keep the belt nice
and tight against your body it's not
going to come loose either you know as a
safety feature that's a really nice
touch once again this does have a
tapered design so in the back it's four
inches wide it's going to give your back
a whole lot of support and in the front
tapers down to around two and a half
inches or so I personally like that you
know it's going to allow you to breathe
properly when you're working out it's
not going to pinch you underneath your
ribs and your skin that can be kind of
annoying you know with other belts out
there now this is pretty standard across
all weight lifting belts you want to
measure around your belly button that
because that's where it's going to be so
there's six different sizes available
for you to purchase from extra small all
the way up to double XL so odds are
there's a belt that's going to fit you I
promise now if you do want a super tight
fit which you most likely do it's
actually best to go down one size from
what you measure so definitely keep that
in mind and another really cool thing
that I like is that Jim Reapers actually
tosses in a one-year replacement
guarantee with this belt so if you
notice any type of manufacturing defects
whether that be from the Buckle or the
stitching or whatever it may be in that
first year you know let them know send
it back they'll send you a new one free
of charge
[Music]
all right so let's go ahead and break
this down for you guys up close and
personal once again this belt does have
a thickness of seven millimeters it's
going to provide you with a whole lot of
support as you're working out it's made
from 100 premium leather and it does it
is paired up with this suede lining
right here it's gonna be really nice and
comfortable if it's on your skin and
it's also going to provide some moisture
control as well so if you're somebody
who sweats a lot as you work out I think
you'll like that I also really like this
dual prong steel Buckle right here it's
going to keep the belt nice and tight
against your body it's just going to
lock everything into place especially
with this little Loop right here you
know this this belt's not going anywhere
trust me and remember you want to
measure around your belly button
whenever you know you're figuring out
which size you want because that's
exactly you know where it's going to be
it's going to be right here around your
belly button and put it on simply slide
that strap in there I have a sweatshirt
on so it's a little different right now
and then just put these prongs in these
holes slide that strap in and you're
good to go it's going to provide you
with a whole lot of support and I really
like this taper right here you know as
you can see like it's not affecting
anything with me you know it's not going
to pinch my ribs pinch my skin it's not
going to negatively impact my breathing
which is something that I think we all
can get on board with
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the gym
Reaper's seven millimeter weightlifting
belt well if you are in fact in the
market for a tapered belt you know I
think this is a really solid option for
you to consider you know it's going to
allow you to be pretty mobile as you're
working out and you know if you're a
power lifter I think you're going to
like this belt as well because it's
going to provide you with a whole lot of
support trust me it's my go-to right now
and this dual prong steel Buckle is a
great safety feature for anybody who's
worried about their belt you know coming
loose on them they're in the middle of
their workout
foreign
so when it comes to those who may not
want to purchase this belt it really
just boils down to your workout style
and your personal preference now if
you're somebody who does a whole lot of
Olympic lifting I think you'll probably
be better off with a nylon belt they
allow you to be more mobile and they're
just overall more versatile some people
may not be crazy about the taper design
since you technically don't have as much
of a surface area for your quarter brace
against some people may also want a
thicker belt than this one right here
because you know it might provide an
even higher level of support the good
news is that Jim Reapers has you covered
on all of those fronts so if I just
described your wants and needs just head
over to their website and I'm sure
you'll find one that suits you best well
that's all she wrote for the gym
Reaper's seven millimeter weightlifting
belt I personally love the taper design
and the fact that it is made from 100
leather now those are just my personal
preferences so if you want your belt to
have some different features I
definitely suggest you know you keep
your search ongoing thanks for hanging
out with me everybody I hope this video
was really helpful and that I was able
to answer any questions you may have
about this belt as always stay posted
for my next video but for now you should
definitely head over to barbin.com and
you can read more about this product
just search bar Bend Jim Reaper's seven
millimeter weightlifting belt review
you'll find all the details everything I
discussed here today I'll see y'all next
time
thank you
foreign